<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>CBC-Bit-Flipping on Ash&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/tags/cbc-bit-flipping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CBC-Bit-Flipping on Ash&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ashutosh1206.github.io/tags/cbc-bit-flipping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>USSH 3.0 - CTFZone</title>
      <link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/ctf/ctfzone18-ussh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/ctf/ctfzone18-ussh/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Points: 138
Challenge Description:
We&amp;rsquo;ve developed a new restricted shell. It also allows to manage user access more securely. Let&amp;rsquo;s try it
nc crypto-01.v7frkwrfyhsjtbpfcppnu.ctfz.one 1337
In this post, I will be discussing my solution for USSH-3.0 challenge from CTFZone which I think is the unintended way. The challenge was quite peculiar, involving “blind” exploit as you will see in this write-up. Some parts of the challenge might look like guessing, but if you read this write-up start-to-end, you will see that it was a well-tailored challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locked Dungeons 2 - Swamp CTF</title>
      <link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/ctf/swamp-locked-dungeons-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/ctf/swamp-locked-dungeons-2/</guid>
      <description>Challenge Points: 498
Challenge Description:
The Dungeon Keeper learned from its mistake. This next lock is protected by even stronger encryption. We’re so close to the final level…there has to be a way in.
The Dark Dungeon series of crypto challenges were the only ones I enjoyed solving in the CTF. Rest of the crypto challenges were pathetic, involved a lot of guessing and were not really crypto challenges and can be called as puzzles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CBC Bit Flipping Attack</title>
      <link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/cbc-bit-flipping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/cbc-bit-flipping/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, the attack on CBC mode of block cipher encryption will be discussed and in the end, detailed writeup for the 16th challenge of Matasano-Crypto-Challenge i.e. about the Bit Flipping Attack in AES-CBC will be provided with explanation!
I want the reader to go through these concepts discussed in the following blog posts, before actually understanding how the CBC Bit-Flipping Attack works:
Mode Detection Oracle Blocksize Detection Oracle We will list down all the information one must have access to, in order to initiate this attack:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
