<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Blogs on Ashutosh Ahelleya</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Ashutosh Ahelleya</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing around with MQTT Protocol</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/mqtt-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/mqtt-protocol/</guid><description>Recently, I happened to come across MQTT Protocol while doing background work for a project as a part of IoT course offered at the University. I liked it due to reasons which I will justify, hence this blog post!
I spent some time yesterday looking at the working and specifications of MQTT v3.1.1 from the blog post by teserakt and through the documentation: http://docs.oasis-open.org/mqtt/mqtt/v3.1.1/mqtt-v3.1.1.html, since I enjoy reading about the protocols and their implementation.</description></item><item><title>Announcing Crypton v1.0</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/crypton-announcement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/crypton-announcement/</guid><description>In this blog post, I will be talking about my new library Crypton, my journey of building this library, future plans and much more!
Check out the library on GitHub: https://github.com/ashutosh1206/Crypton
Introduction This library is an attempt by the author to help provide a platform to learn and practice Offensive and Defensive cryptography for people interested in this field .
With the increasing number of attacks on implementations of cryptographic protocols every year, it has become essential that we give as much importance to secure implementation of these protocols as we give to internals of the protocol itself.</description></item><item><title>Finite Fields - Number Theory</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/finite-fields/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/finite-fields/</guid><description>This blog post covers one of the most important Mathematical Structures for Cryptography- Fields. It is used in both Symmetric and Asymmetric key Cryptography.
This blog post gives a basic introduction to Finite Fields and arithmetic operations on it, but I hope the purpose of it is served- to make people, who don’t have basic knowledge about this, understand a few upcoming CTF write-ups, that are based on Finite Fields.</description></item><item><title>Blinding Attack on RSA Signatures</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/rsa-blinding-attack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/rsa-blinding-attack/</guid><description>This blog primarily focuses on Blinding Attack- an elementary vulnerability in unpadded RSA digital signature algorithm that can be exploited to forge signatures. The working and properties of Digital Signatures will be described before directly jumping onto the attack. In the end, we discuss ways to prevent this attack.
Unpadded Digital Signatures using RSA RSA is a kind of Trapdoor One-way Function. Wikipedia describes a one-way function as a function that is easy to compute on every input, but hard to invert given the image of a random input.</description></item><item><title>Polynomial Interpolation</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/polynomial-interpolation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/polynomial-interpolation/</guid><description>I have been reading the paper &amp;ndash; “How to Share a Secret” in detail for the past few weeks, a revolutionary research paper written by Adi Shamir. This paper, applies some of the concepts of Number Theory and Algebra, one of which is polynomial interpolation, and has been used to construct a secure and reliable key management system. The theorem is simple and easy to understand, and has been applied in the best way one ever could.</description></item><item><title>CBC Bit Flipping Attack</title><link>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/cbc-bit-flipping/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ashutosh1206.github.io/blog/cbc-bit-flipping/</guid><description>In this blog post, the attack on CBC mode of block cipher encryption will be discussed and in the end, detailed writeup for the 16th challenge of Matasano-Crypto-Challenge i.e. about the Bit Flipping Attack in AES-CBC will be provided with explanation!
I want the reader to go through these concepts discussed in the following blog posts, before actually understanding how the CBC Bit-Flipping Attack works:
Mode Detection Oracle Blocksize Detection Oracle We will list down all the information one must have access to, in order to initiate this attack:</description></item></channel></rss>